Shut up! - What do you want?
!שתוק ?מה אתם רוצים-
Knock! Be quiet.
.אל תזוז. תדפוק! שקט
Hello, love. - Shut up, don't move.
.שלום, אהובי .שקט! לא לזוז-
Please, don't hurt me. - Move!
!אל תעשו לי כלום !קדימה-
Move, c'mon! Go in, move!
!קדימה, לזוז! קדימה
Move!
!לזוז
Stay there, don't speak.
.אל תזוזו ואל תדברו
Sit there and don't move.
.שבו ואל תזוזו
Give me the phone. Santiago, go in there.
.הטלפון. סנטיאגו, תיכנס
Everybody out and go in there.
.כולם לצאת וללכת לשם
What's going on? - Come out, move!
?מה קורה כאן !קדימה, לזוז-
Get down here, on the floor. Move!
!קדימה, על הרצפה. קדימה
Get down on the floor and don't move.
.על הרצפה ולא לזוז
Who's in here? Come out.
!מי כאן? החוצה
You go too, move! On your knees, like them.
!גם אתם, קדימה .על הרצפה כמו כולם
Go get the wallets in the rooms.
.לכי להביא את הארנקים מהחדרים
Don't move. Keep still! Don't move!
.לא לזוז !לא לזוז! לא לזוז
Put it in here, hurry!
.תכניסי לכאן, מהר
Everyone get up and go in there, quick!
!כולם לקום ולהיכנס. מהר
Move, you too!
!גם אתה
Are you still here? Move!
!אתה עדיין כאן? זוז
Get on your knees. You too. On your knees. Let's go.
.על הברכיים, כולם !על הברכיים, קדימה
Carmine, I got everyone's wallets?
.קרמינה, הארנקים של כולם אצלי
Get up! Where do you keep the money? - In there.
?את, קומי! איפה הכסף .שם-
What the fuck are you doing? - You shut up!
?מה לעזאזל אתם עושים !שקט-
You shut up! Shut up!
!שקט! לשתוק
Shut up, you hear me? Shut up or I'll kill you.
.תשתקי. שמעת אותי? תשתקי
Give me the money, hurry up.
!תני לי את הכסף, מהר
It's all here, I swear. Now go, please!
.הכול כאן, אני נשבעת !לכו, בבקשה
Santiago, let's go!
!סנטיאגו, זזים
The Holy Virgin sent you, Donna Patrizia.
,הבתולה הקדושה שלחה אותך .דונה פטריציה
Hello?
?הלו
Okay, be right there.
.טוב, אני כבר מגיעה
We gotta go. - All right.
.צריך לזוז .בסדר-
Donna Patrizia, excuse me. - Watch it! Mind your manners.
.דונה פטריציה, סליחה ?תיזהר! איפה הנימוסים שלך-
It's important.
.זה חשוב
Don't worry, tomorrow we'll fix everything.
.אל תדאג, מחר נטפל בכול
Thanks anyway.
.תודה בכל מקרה
Let's see if you learnt...
.נראה אם למדת משהו
Who is in charge here?
?מי האחראית כאן
Patrizia.
.פטריציה
Donna Patrizia! Who is it, your sister?
!דונה פטריציה .היא לא אחות שלך
What do you say? - Donna Patrizia.
?מה אומרים .דונה פטריציה-
Louder!
!חזק יותר
Scumbags, wash your mouth out before you say her name.
מנוולים, תשטפו טוב את הפה .לפני שאתם אומרים את שמה
Nicola.
.ניקולה
Whose kids are you?
?מי ההורים שלכם
No one.
.אף אחד
Dad's in jail in Secondigliano.
.אבא בכלא בסקונדיגליאנו
And your mom?
?ואימא שלכם
Mom...
...אימא
Mom's dead.
.אימא מתה
Where do you live? - In Secondigliano.
?איפה אתם גרים .בסקונדיגליאנו-
With my big sister and a little brother.
.עם אחותי הגדולה ועם אחי הקטן
You and your brother are just kids, but here you grow up fast.
.אתה ואחיך סך הכול ילדים
Don't forget that.
.אל תשכח את זה
Leave him alone. - What?
.עזוב אותו ?מה-
Nicola, come.
.ניקולה, בוא
Do they belong to anyone?
?הם שייכים למישהו
They work on their own, they're not under anyone.
,הם פועלים לבד .הם לא כפופים לאף אחד
They need to understand how the world works.
.הם צריכים להבין איך העולם פועל .בסדר-
Get them a job and stay on them.
.תמצא להם עבודה ותשגיח עליהם
They're a couple of pissants who don't listen to no one.
הם שני מושתנים .שלא מקשיבים לאף אחד
Can we trust them? - We'll see.
?אפשר לסמוך עליהם
Nicola...
.ניקולה
I know you think you should command with a stick,
אני יודעת שאתה חושב .שצריך מקל כדי לשלוט
but then the stick breaks and you've seen it.
,אבל בסוף המקל נשבר .כבר ראית את זה
We gotta change strategy.
.מוכרחים לשנות אסטרטגיה
Where have you been? I've been looking for you all day.
?איפה הייתם .חיפשתי אתכם כל היום
Give it to me, I'll show you how to play.
.תן לי, אני אראה לך איך לשחק
Well?
?נו, מה
What have you done?
?מה עשית
What happened to you?
?מה קרה לך? מה עשיתם
Nothing.
.שום דבר
Santiago, what happened?
?סנטיאגו, מה קרה
I said nothing happened, all right?
?אמרתי שלא קרה שום דבר! ברור
It's you, it's always you. You're leading him down the wrong path.
!זה אתה. זה תמיד אתה .אתה מקלקל גם אותו
Leave the kid alone, I don't want him to end up like you.
,תעזוב את הילד .אני לא רוצה שהוא ייצא כמוך
What are you gonna do about it?
?כן? למה מה תעשי
He's still gotta eat, I didn't prepare anything yet, you take care of it.
.הוא צריך לאכול .לא בישלתי, תדאג לזה אתה
BOLOGNA CENTRAL STATION
- תחנה מרכזית בולוניה -
Want anything? - Another time.
?תרצי משהו .בפעם אחרת-
There's a million euros in the car out front, for the down payment.
יש בחוץ מכונית .עם מיליון אירו, למקדמה
Serge, go get it.
.סרגיי, לך להביא
When the job's done, you get the rest. - All right.
.תקבל את השאר בסיום העבודה .בסדר-
Why didn't we see each other in Naples?
?למה לא נפגשנו בנאפולי
Problems? - No, I had stuff to do in Bologna.
?יש בעיות .לא, יש לי סידורים בבולוניה-
Can I help you? - There should be a booking for Ferreri.
?במה אפשר לעזור
Fifth floor, room 501. - Thank you.
.קומה חמישית, חדר 501
Counselor.
.אדוני הפרקליט
Did you find it easily? - No problem.
?הגעת בקלות .בטח-
This way, counselor.
.בבקשה, אדוני
This is the sales contract for the dump.
.זה חוזה המכירה של המזבלה
For you there's 20,000 euros up front, a repayment schedule for the bank debt
,אתה תקבל 20,000 אירו מראש הסדר תשלומים לחוב בבנק
and we'll give you something for the bank guarantees.
וגם ניתן לך משהו .על הערבויות הבנקאיות
And then?
?ואז
There's time for the paperwork to go through before closing.
יידרש עוד קצת זמן .עד שהמסמכים יטופלו והכול ייסגר
Meanwhile, I'll put a figurehead in, one of our guys.
,בינתיים אציב מנהל בובה .אחד מהאנשים שלנו
I don't have any intention at 60
.אני כבר בן 60
of having them come to get me at six in the morning.
אני ממש לא רוצה .שיבואו לקחת אותי בשש בבוקר
You need to relax.
.אתה צריך להירגע
You're in clover.
.אתה יכול לישון בשקט
All I want is reassurance that you're doing things by the book.
אני רק רוצה להיות בטוח .שאתם עושים הכול לפי הספר
I'm handing you a structure... - Pasanelli...
...אני מעביר לכם מבנה .פסנלי-
You've always tried to do things by the book, right?
תמיד ניסית לעשות הכול ?לפי הספר, נכון
And what have you accomplished?
?ומה השגת
In two years 500,000 euros profit and 800,000 in debt.
בתוך שנתיים 500,000 ברווחים .ו-800,000 בחובות
If I come here now and I repay those debts,
אם אני בא לכאן עכשיו ,ופורע את החובות האלה
do you think I'm doing it all by the book?
נראה לך שאני עושה ?הכול לפי הספר
No.
.לא
Yo, what do you want? - A piece.
?היי, מה אתה רוצה .חתיכה-
Give me a piece.
.חתיכה
Let's go.
.בוא נזוז
So little?
?זה הכול
Boys...
...ילדים
after what you did it's too much.
בהתחשב במה שעשיתם .זה יותר מדי
Now get out of here.
.עופו מכאן
You did a good job.
.עשיתם עבודה טובה
If you behave, there's a monthly payment for you too.
תתנהגו יפה .ותקבלו גם תשלום חודשי
Thank you. - Thank you.
.תודה .תודה-
The deal with our friend is done.
.העסקה עם החבר שלנו סגורה
Good, it's already full here. - All the paperwork's done.
.יופי, כבר מלא כאן .כל המסמכים מוכנים-
We can send the garbage to the new plant from tomorrow.
מחר נוכל להתחיל לשלוח .את הזבל למפעל החדש
How the fuck can you stand this disgusting stink?
איך לעזאזל ?אתה סובל את הסירחון הזה
In the last three days we've treated three tons of garbage.
בשלושת הימים האחרונים .טיפלנו בשלוש טונות אשפה
That shit is the finished product, ready to be trucked out.
,זה המוצר הסופי .הוא מוכן למשלוח
The construction business is the biggest we have.
עסק הבנייה .הוא הגדול ביותר שלנו
And we have as much raw material as we need, infinite.
,ויש לנו אין סוף חומר גלם .כמה שרק נרצה
All good? - Yes.
?הכול בסדר .כן-
Soon, tons of reinforced concrete will be ready.
בקרוב יהיו לנו .טונות של בטון מזוין
Are you coming back?
?אתה חוזר
I still have something to do in Bologna. I'm staying overnight.
.יש לי עוד עניין בבולוניה, אבא .אני אשאר לישון
Dad? - All right.
?אבא .בסדר-
It's just you didn't tell me where we're going tonight,
.לא אמרת לי לאן נלך הערב
so I bought this.
.לכן קניתי את זה
It's a surprise, I told you.
.זו הפתעה, אמרתי לך
Don't be silly! How do I look?
!די עם השטויות ?איך אני נראית
You look beautiful, Patrizia.
.את יפהפייה, פטריציה
Hand me the cape, I'll put it away for you.
,תני לי השכמייה .אני אניח לך אותה בצד
Sure.
.בטח
I'll be right back.
.אני כבר חוזר
May I?
.סליחה
Mickey! - My man!
!מיקי !אחי-
Dude! - How are you?
!אחי ?מה שלומך-
Good! I'm glad you came. - Me too. This is Patrizia.
.מעולה! אני שמח שבאת .גם אני. תכיר את פטריציה-
Fabio, my pleasure.
.שלום. אני פאביו, נעים מאוד
I'm the guy who put up with five years of university with the out-of-towner.
אני זה שסבל את הכפרי הזה .חמש שנים באוניברסיטה
You put up with me?
?אתה סבלת אותי
And where are you from? - Naples.
?ומאיפה את .נאפולי-
You know Mickey, right? In the end, he went home.
?אתה מכיר את מיקי, לא
He did the right thing. And what do you do, Patrizia?
.בחירה נכונה
I do more or less what he does.
.בערך מה שהוא עושה
Let's go in here.
.ניכנס לכאן
Let's park here.
.נחנה כאן
Excuse me! Two vodka shots.
.סליחה! שני שוטים של וודקה
Mickey! - Eleonora!
.מיקי .אליאונורה-
How are you? - Good, you?
?מה שלומך ?בסדר. ומה איתך-
All good. This is Patrizia.
.בסדר גמור. זו פטריציה
Nice to meet you, Eleonora. - Nice to meet you.
.נעים מאוד. אליאונורה .נעים מאוד-
What are you doing here? - We came to get a drink. You?
?מה אתה עושה כאן ?באנו לשתות קצת. מה איתך-
I always come here.
.אני תמיד באה לכאן
It's good to see you. - Me too.
.טוב לראות אותך .כנ"ל-
Right... How long are you staying?
?טוב. לכמה זמן באתם
Just long enough to have a drink.
.מספיק זמן כדי לשתות
Mickey... wait.
.מיקי... רגע
All right. Maybe I'll see you later. - Maybe.
.בסדר. אולי נתראה אחר כך .אולי-
Everything okay, Patrizia?
?הכול בסדר, פטריציה
It's no good, you need to change it.
.לא טעים. תחליף
Sorry, can you make another one? It's no good.
?סליחה! אפשר לקבל חדש .הוא לא טעים
Patrizia!
!פטריציה
Patrizia, stop!
!פטריציה, חכי
I'm Carmine, he's my brother Santiago.
.אני קרמינה וזה אחי סנטיאגו
Pleasure, Ilenia.
.נעים מאוד. אני אילניה .נעים מאוד-
She's Anna. - Pleasure.
.זאת אנה .נעים מאוד. -נעים מאוד-
Wanna dance? - Let's dance.
?רוצה לרקוד .בוא-
Want some coke? - No, I got no money.
?רוצה קוקאין .אין לי כסף-
It's a present. - Wait.
.מתנה .חכה-
What happened?
?מה קרה
He wants to give us some coke, what do we do?
.הוא רוצה לתת לנו קוקאין ?מה נעשה
What do we do? We take it.
.מה נעשה? ניקח
Okay, let's go.
.טוב, קדימה
Turn it off. - No, or else they'll hear us.
.תסגרי .לא, אחרת ישמעו אותנו-
Santiago, got something to snort with? - No, nothing.
?סנטיאגו, יש לך עם מה להסניף .שום דבר-
You got anything?
?יש לך משהו
Turn off the water. - Here.
.תסגרי את הברז .קח-
Got any more? - Wait here.
?יש לך עוד .חכי כאן-
What are you going to do? We're outta cash. - You'll see.
.מה תעשה? נגמר לנו הכסף
Give me 20. - Another one?
.תביא 20 ?עוד-
Another one.
.עוד
Bro', you got five?
?אחי, יש לך 5
Guys!
!בחורים
You find it? Let's go.
.מצאת? בוא
Catch those little shits!
!תתפסו את המניאקים! הנה הם
There they are, turn around.
!הנה הם. תסתובב
Turn!
.תסתובב
We'll go in this way.
.בוא לכאן
Guys, they're up there.
.חברים, הם שם
We found them, hurry up.
.מצאנו אותם. מהר
Come out! Better for everyone if you do!
!צאו החוצה !זה יהיה עדיף לכולם
There they are, little shits.
.הנה המניאקים הקטנים
Now you run away, piece of shit! Now you have to run away!
!עכשיו אתה בורח, חתיכת חרא !עכשיו אתה בורח
Did you have fun being an asshole?
?נהנית להיות זבל
Did you have fun, you piece of shit?
?נהנית, חתיכת חרא
What the fuck are you doing on our turf?
מה לעזאזל ?אתם עושים בשטח שלנו
Who do you belong to? - We're from Secondigliano.
?למי אתם שייכים
We're under Patrizia.
.אנחנו כפופים לפטריציה
That ugly bitch Patrizia brings her trash onto our turf?
הכלבה המכוערת מכניסה ?את הזבל שלה לשטח שלנו
Is that right? - They're just talking shit, Enzo.
?כן
Let's take it easy, guys.
.בואו נירגע, חברים
I'm not getting my hands dirty with Patrizia's shit.
אני לא מלכלך את הידיים שלי .בחרא של פטריציה
Patrizia?
?פטריציה
Good morning. - Good morning.
.בוקר טוב
Welcome back, Donna Patrizia.
.ברוך שובך, דונה פטריציה
Hi, Nicola.
.היי, ניקולה
Leave us.
.החוצה
Well?
?נו
Sorry, Donna Patrizia. - Yeah, sorry...
.סליחה, דונה פטריציה ...כן, סליחה-
How could you?
?איך יכולתם
I stick my neck out to give you an opportunity
אני עושה מעל ומעבר ...כדי לעזור לכם
and how do you repay me?
?וככה אתם אומרים תודה
You go dicking around in Forcella?
?עושים שטויות בפורצ'לה
We were just joking. - Joking?
.זו הייתה סתם בדיחה ?בדיחה-
If it was a joke, why aren't you laughing, Carmine?
אם זו הייתה בדיחה ?למה אתה לא צוחק, קרמינה
No, Donna Patrizia! Please!
!לא, דונה פטריציה
He's my little slave, he does everything I tell him to.
.הוא השפוט שלי .הוא עושה מה שאני אומר לו
Take it out on me, not my brother.
.תוציאי את זה עליי, לא על אחי
Carmine...
.קרמינה
It's not that I don't want to be defied by two snot-noses like you...
העניין הוא לא שאני לא רוצה .ששני פרחחים כמוכם ימרו את פי
It's just that I can't.
.אני פשוט לא יכולה להרשות לעצמי
Make them disappear.
.תיפטרו מהם
Hello, Enzo.
.שלום, אנזו
Thank you, I took care of it personally.
.תודה. טיפלתי בזה בעצמי
What will we tell their family now?
?מה נגיד למשפחה שלהם עכשיו
They only had a sister.
.הייתה להם רק אחות
If they come, tell them I treat everyone in Secondigliano like my children.
אם יבואו תגידו להם שמבחינתי .כולם בסקונדיגליאנו הם הילדים שלי
But if they disrespect me, they have to pay.
.אבל אם מזלזלים בי צריך לשלם
Good evening. Would you like to order?
?ערב טוב. תרצי להזמין
Can you send him to me?
?את יכולה לשלוח אותו אליי
All right.
.בסדר
I'm sorry, he says he can't.
.סליחה, הוא אומר שהוא לא יכול
Can I help you?
?אפשר לעזור לך
No, thanks.
.לא, תודה
Who was she?
?מי זאת
Nobody.
.אף אחת